Left with nothing. Capable of anything.
Widows is a crime, thriller, drama film directed by Steve McQueen.
A police shootout leaves four thieves dead during an
explosive armed robbery attempt in Chicago.
Their widows have nothing in common except a debt left
behind by their spouses' criminal activities.
Hoping to forge a future on their own terms, they
join forces to pull off a heist.
Veronica Rawlings, played by Viola Davis.
Linda, played by Michelle Rodriguez.
Alice, played by Elizabeth Debicki.
Belle, played by Cynthia Erivo.
Jack Mulligan, played by Colin Farrell.
Tom Mulligan, played by Robert Duvall.
Widows is a 2018 neo-noir heist thriller film directed by Steve McQueen from a screenplay by Gillian
Flynn and McQueen, based upon the 1983 British television series of the same name.
The plot follows four Chicago women who attempt to steal $5 million from the home of a prominent local politician in order to pay
back a crime boss missing money stolen by the women's husbands before they were killed in a botched getaway attempt.
A British-American co-production, the film stars Viola Davis, Michelle Rodriguez and Elizabeth Debicki in the title roles alongside Cynthia Erivo (in her film
debut), Colin Farrell, Brian Tyree Henry, Daniel Kaluuya, Jacki Weaver, Carrie Coon, Robert Duvall, and Liam Neeson in an ensemble supporting cast.
Widows premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2018, and was theatrically released in
the United Kingdom on November 6, 2018, and in the United States on November 16, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received critical acclaim, with praise aimed at its direction, editing, screenplay and performances (particularly
Davis, Debicki and Kaluuya), with critics crediting it for blending "dramatic themes with popcorn thrills".
The film grossed $76 million worldwide on a production budget of $42 million and received several award
nominations, among them being one for Davis for the BAFTA Award for Best Actress in a Leading Role.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois,
politics, politician, heist, flashback.
The tone is emotional and intense.